Ayanleye S. Oluwatoyin

Junior Penetration Tester

💌 ayanleyetoyin@outlook.com 🔇 nullcell8822.github.io 📞 +2349020674624 💡 Lagos, Nigeria

Summary

A young professional starting out in the Cybersecurity field working to be a Penetration Tester, skilled in scripting, web application vulnerability assessment, network security, firmware development and embedded application development. Currently working on Bug Bounties and open source web application code review and testing as well as developing an automation script for carrying out reconnaissance, vulnerability discovery and testing that would otherwise be done manually. Continuously learning using platforms such as HackTheBox, TryHackMe, PawnTillDawn and VulnHub. Also preparing for the OSCP Certification Exam.

Skills

Languages and Frameworks: Python, C, C++, Bash, Yocto

Toolsets and OS: Linux, Windows, GitHub, Git, Wireshark, Nessus, VMware, Metasploit, Burpsuite **Hardware:** Reading Schematics, Circuit Prototyping, Referencing HW datasheets, Raspberry Pi, Arduino **Technical Skills:** Web Application Penetration Testing, Network Vulnerability Testing, Password Cracking

Projects

Automated Network Domain Scanning Tool

- Custom Automated Scanner for Web and Networks. It works using modules and plugins to each module to extend functionality.
- It automates common manual Penetration Testing practices and is continuously developed using publicly available information and personal experiences.
- Current modules include Domain Recon for Bug Bounties and Network Automated Scanning and Exploit Suggestion.
- The project is still in early stages and as such the repo is still private.

Pentesting Environment Setup Tool

Bash script for one line install of most penetration testing tools for Debian based Linux Distributions e.g. AWS VPS and Raspberry Pi 4 (64-bit)

Visis Glasses

Prototype product for Vinsighte Technology, which is their product for the visually impaired

Vixen Modular Pet

A modular robotic pet with obstacle detection and 2 behaviors, based on the TIVA LaunchPad

Unmaned Ground Vehicle

An autonomous tracked UGV for a final year project, based on an Arduino Mega

Ardupilot Based Drone

Made a drone using the ardupilot flight controller and adding a master microcontroller for autonomous control

Employment

M4xH3dr00m - Team Member - Nigeria

July 2021 to Present

M4xH3dr00m is a group of young cybersecurity talents who engage in CTFs, Bug Bounties, Red Teaming and others freelance work.

Linux Professional Institute Innovation Hub - Intern - Appleton Road, Ibadan

March 2020 to December 2020

Aiding in the development of embedded projects for members and their clients as well as teaching Embedded Systems and training in Cybersecurity

Vinsighte - Embedded Software Developer - Appleton Road, University of Ibadan, Ibadan

October 2019 to April 2020

Development of prototype for reading glasses for the visually impaired

Education

University of Ibadan

February 2017 to Present

B.Sc Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2022

September 2012 to July 2016

Trinity International College, Ofada

September 2010 to July 2012

Hacking Platforms

TryHackMe - NullCell - tryhackme.com/p/NullCell

TryHackMe is a free online platform for learning cyber security, using hands-on exercises and labs, all through your browser

HackTheBox - NullCell - hackthebox.eu/home/users/profile/462764

The International School Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ago-Iwoye

Hack The Box is a massive, online cyber security training platform, allowing individuals, companies, universities and all kinds of organizations around the world to level up their hacking skills

PwnTillDawn - NullCell - online.pwntilldawn.com/Achievements/2087

PwnTillDawn Online Battlefield is wizlynx group's vision of the next-generation offensive security & Penetration testing lab but also capture-the-flag competition

Volunteering

Google Developer Student Club - University of Ibadan - Cybersecurity Lead

October 2021 to Present

Ibadan, Nigeria

Training students who want to get into the field of Cybersecurity.

IEEE-UISB - Embedded Team Lead University of Ibadan

Worked on maze solving RC cars

October 2019 to October 2021

Awards

Cyber Talents Nationals CTF - Nigeria 1st Place - Cyber Talents

September 2021

Cyber Talents' Annual CTF National for Nigeria to qualify for Africa and Middle-East Challenge

American Business Council Cybersecurity CTF 2nd Place - American Business Council

September 2021

A CTF hosted by The American Business Council Nigeria for Cybersecurity Professionals

Hackathon Winner - CampusLabs with US Embassy

April 2019

A disability hackathon to find solutions to help people with various kinds of disabilities. My solution proposed a design for an autom

Hult Prize - Hult Prize Foundation

October 2018

Hult prize UI for creating jobs for 10,000 people withing the next 10 years.